





# **Dmitry Zorikhin**



A dynamic Data Scientist with related industrial experience. Initiated and managed various data science and digital transformation products across Oil and Gas (US, Russia), Steel manufacturing (India, Russia) and Financial industries (US, Malta). Portfolio: <a href="https://dzorikhin.github.io/portfolio/">https://dzorikhin.github.io/portfolio/</a>

#### PROFESSIONAL WORK EXPERIENCE

## Senior Associate | Data Scientist

May 2021 - Dec 2021

PwC Malta, Digital Transformation - Financial Services, Malta

- Developed financial statements data extraction tool and automated ETL pipeline
- · Dashboard development for data visualization and descriptive analytics for C-level decision making
- Initiated 3 data science projects within Assurance and Tax departments
- Coaching junior staff

Tech stack: Python | Classical ML | Timeseries analysis | SQL | Power BI

Data Scientist July 2020 – March 2021

NLMK Group, Digital Transformation – Metallurgy, Yekaterinburg, Russia

- Managed 4 digital products at MVP/production stage with \$400,000/year overall economic benefit
- Led the group of 5 Data Science contractors
- Initiated 2 innovative projects for production upgrade (laser cutting technology, hydrostatic pressure monitoring)
- Implemented AR remote expert for the first time in the company
- Created Value Stream Map for Electrical Steel production within NLMK Group

Tech stack: Python | Classical ML | CNN | RNN | Timeseries analysis | SQL | GitLab | Hadoop | Spark | Docker

# **Data Scientist (remote)**

June 2019 – July 2020

Advisor Energy, Digital Transformation - Oil & Gas, Houston, USA / Yekaterinburg, Russia

- Developed data-driven forecasting model for shale oil & gas production with 95% accuracy using derived decline/type curve parameters
- Prepared 8 US oil & gas shale basin reports covering over 80 E&P assets using quarterly updated financial and technical companies' data
- Excluded the use of paid services for infographics by using open-source graphing library Plotly
- Data-driven Net Asset Value models | Type/Decline curves analytics | Reserves | Completions

Tech stack: Python | JavaScript | Classical ML | RNN | Timeseries analysis | AWS | SQL | Power BI | Git | Docker

Lead Data Analyst

March 2019 – June 2019

SKB Kontur, Business Analytics – Software Development, Yekaterinburg, Russia

• Saved \$40,000/month as the result of notification services analysis of lead company's product Kontur.Extern

Tech stack: SQL | GitLab | Python | Classical ML

#### **Completion and Well Intervention Engineer**

Nov 2015 - March 2019

Sakhalin Energy Investment Company Ltd. (Shell and Gazprom JV) - Oil & Gas, Yuzhno-Sakhalinsk, Russia

- Saved \$2mln/well by optimizing well completion timing execution using engineering data model database
- Initiated and got financial approval for joint cloud-based data project for Wells and Subsurface departments
- Reduced CAPEX by \$50,000/well optimizing completion string for workover projects
- Led well delivery projects with over 20 people involved as contributing parties

## Associate Scientist | Engineer

Nov 2009 - Aug 2014

Ural Federal University | Labfer Ltd. - Science (Physics), Yekaterinburg, Russia

- Won and led own grant for scientific research with total amount of funds over \$13,000
- Developed ferroelectric substrates bonding technology for engineering project execution worth \$260,000
- Patent owner "Hysteresis-free High-Temperature Precise Bimorph Actuators" as part of project team

## **EDUCATION**

MSc Offshore Oil and Gas Engineering	2014 – 2015
Diploma with Distinction, Robert Gordon University, Aberdeen, UK	
Postgraduate studies in the Physics of Condensed Matter Physics Department, Ural Federal University, Yekaterinburg, Russia	2013 – 2014
MSc in Innovations Diploma with Distinction, Physics Department, Ural Federal University, Yekaterinburg, Russia	2011 – 2013
BSc of Engineering and Technology in Innovations Physics Department, Ural Federal University, Yekaterinburg, Russia	2007 – 2011

# SKILLS, ADDITIONAL ACHIEVEMENTS AND RELEVANT CERTIFICATES

- Coursera, Codecademy, Skillbox Data Science courses
- Google Cloud Big Data and Machine Learning Fundamentals
- Practice-oriented Machine Learning Zoomcamp course
- Obtained the highest individual performance factor among peers for the last 3 years within Sakhalin Energy